Matthias Müringer

Full-Stack Web Developer

https://matthiasmueringer.de

github.com/koola123

@MatthiasMueringer

+49 (0) 176 744 27 691

n linkedin.com/in/matthiasmueringer

mmueringer@web.de
Wiesbaden, Germany

Certified web dev with strong creative, analytical skills, and an eye-for-detail in building customized web pages. Possesses business acumen and experience working in multicultural and cross-border teams, and brings especially skills in selling products and services that require explanation and perseverance. A strong analytical and goal-oriented approach to fit for any kind of team in the development process of innovative solutions.

MAJOR WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

MyFlix App https://myflix-movies-client.netlify.app/

A full-fledged full-stack web application. On the frontend with a beautiful responsive webpage with routing, rich interactions, several interface views, and a polished user experience. It was created with React and Redux for state management. On the backend a REST API will provide users with access to information about different movies, directors and genres. Users will be able to sign up, update their personal information, and create a list of their favorite movies. It was created with Node.js, Express and using modern API structure. A MongoDB database was created to store all the data.

Meet App https://koola123.github.io/meet/

It shows upcoming full-stack meetups around the world. A serverless, progressive web application (PWA) with React using a test-driven development (TDD) technique. The application uses the Google Calendar API and Serverless functions (AWS lambda) for the authorization server instead of using a traditional server to fetch the events.

CODING & PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCES

IT Bootcamp graduate

CareerFoundry | April 2021 - May 2023

- Completed CareerFoundry's Full-Stack Web Development program.
- Designed and deployed several web applications on GitHub.

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCES

Senior Sales Manager

Yourfirm | February 2022 - February 2023

• Selling job advertisements and recruiting products to SMEs in Germany with an adjusted sales target according to the position, getting into commission faster, which resulted in a better sales bonus.

Key Account Manager

Yourfirm | February 2022 - February 2023

- Selling job advertisements and recruiting products to SMEs in Germany. With an unique selling point, the number of new accounts could be increased significantly in a short amount of time.
- Created sales reports and did forecast planning for the upcoming months to keep on track with the annual sales target, which was achieved with a higher account growth.

Sales Consultant

Monster Worldwide | January 2020 - December 2020

• B-2-B Sales of job advertisements and recruiting solutions to SMEs in Germany. Takeover of existing customers and acquisition of new companies via cold calling. More contracts were closed by the end of 2020.

Account Manager Telesales CH New Business

Monster Worldwide | June 2019 - December 2019

• B-2-B Selling of job advertisements and recruiting solutions to the Swiss market with a good product mix to offer tailor-made solutions. Result: Revenue maximization by 25%.

Consultant IT & Technology

Robert Half | October 2018 - February 2019

• Recruitment of IT-specialists, conducting interviews and placing candidates to companies via

Active Sourcing over Xing, Linkedin and Social Media. Attending job fairs to get in contact with new talents.

• Negotiating contracts with potential B-2-B customers, and building long term relationships in the IT sector to increase sales. Result: One software developer placement to a newly acquired customer in four month since job start.

Account Manager North & East Germany

Hertz Corporation | February 2013 - September 2018

- New customer acquisition and existing customer care to SMEs.
- Definition of requirements and preparation of quotations and tenders based on the rental needs of companies.
- Selling short- and long-term rentals like Hertz Minilease (a competitive long-term rental option for private customers).
- Competitor monitoring (Sixt, Europear, Avis, Enterprise) on the German car rental and fleet market and derivation of recommendations for actions in consultation with the Key Account Manager and Head of Telesales.
- Monthly reporting of sales volume for new contracts and definition of new KPIs. Result: Market shares and levels of awareness of the Hertz, Dollar and Thrifty brands could be increased by 45% compared to the previous year.

SKILLS

Technical

JavaScript, React, Redux Node.js/Express.js

TypeScript, Angular

React Native

HTML5/CSS3/SASS

Bootstrap

MongoDB, SQL

Git, GitHub

Test Driven Development
Progressive Web Applications

AWS Lambda Functions

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development CareerFoundry, Berlin (Germany)

2021 - 2023

B.A. in Business Administration

South Westphalia University of Applied

Sciences, Meschede (Germany)

2014 - 2015

Business Administration (VWA)

VWA, Wiesbaden (Germany)

2008 - 2012

BRITA SE

Industrial Management Assistant

Taunusstein (Germany)

2004 - 2006

LANGUAGES

English (B2/C1)

German (Native)

HOBBIES / INTERESTS

Photography, hiking, travelling, museums, cafes, time with my family